Roxane Connick Carlisle collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 4: Moving image items
  The moving image items that have been digitized have not been processed, and the ID numbers differ from their analog sources.
  - CBC and Radio Canada (Montreal): interview on Femme aujord'hui by Aline Desjardin, November 2, 1977, 1 videocassette (U-Matic; 60 min.): analog. (Item id AFC 2012/008: MV01)
    Subject: Roxane Carlisle - CIDA (Canadian International Development Agency) duties - personal.
  - Roxane Carlisle: interview with Ahmed Diraige, April 1974, 1 videocassette (VHS; 60 min.): analog. (Item id AFC 2012/008: MV02)
    Made at CIDA.
  - The Sudan I know: interview with Roxane Carlisle, 1984, 1 videocassette (VHS; 33 min.): analog. (Item id AFC 2012/008: MV03)
    The label on the videocassette suggests this was made at the Center de préparation des cooperants, in the briefing centre.
  - Unidentified film, 1 safety film: analog. (Item id AFC 2012/008: MV04)
- Series 5: Artifacts
  - 1 guinea fowl feather, AFC 2012/008: AR01 (Box 5)
    Formerly mounted to a page in the photo album. The feather measures approximately 8 inches long.
- Appendix A: Ethnic groups
  - Anuak
  - Baggara--Beni Helba (sub-tribe)
  - Baggara--Hawazma
  - Baggara--Ma'aliya (sub-tribe)
  - Baggara--Ta'isha
  - Baggara--Zaghawi
  - Bederiya
  - Beja--Haddendoa (sub-division)
  - Dinka
  - Fellata (Fula)
  - Fur of Girri
  - Hamar
  - Nuba
  - Nuer
  - Pari Lokoro of Lafon Hill
  - Shilluk
- Appendix B: Musical instruments
  - Aerophone--ambaya
  - Aerophone--bursa or bukhsa (hollow groud)
  - Aerophone--jekeh or karou
  - Aerophone--keita
  - Aerophone--kwi
  - Aerophone--ndon (gourd)
  - Aerophone--sorrow
  - Drum--age
  - Drum--bidi
  - Drum--bul
  - Drum--clay pot
  - Drum--congo
  - Drum--copper
  - Drum--daluka
  - Drum--dluka (earthenware drum)
  - Drum--meki
  - Drum--nahass
  - Drum--nugarra
  - Drum--rebab
  - Drum--tomoroleh
  - Drum--tumba
  - Drum--tumblè
  - Bagpipes
  - Chordophone--umkiki (one-stringed chordophone)
  - Elbow bells
  - Idiophone--dinger (water and gourd idiophone)
  - Kudu horn (antelope)
  - Kuri horn (cattle)
  - Lyre (not an oud)
  - Lyre--pirimbiri
  - Murnèh flute
  - Oud (UF ud)
  - Tiutiu (small antelope horn)
Bibliography
Carlisle, Roxane Connick. "Women Singers in Darfur, Sudan Republic." Anthropos, Bd. 68, H. 5/6 (1973), pp. 785-800. https://www.jstor.org/stable/40459594
el Kably, Abdel Karim. Sudan: the Music and Songs of Abdel Karim el Kably. Afrotone STLP-500, 196u. https://lccn.loc.gov/71751003